all right I had this about 30 seconds
before I went live so I created a URL
that that honestly is not any easier
than the stream yard URL in fact to me
it's a little more complex but anyway if
you would like to join on camera you can
follow that or there is a stream yard
link in the description which is just
the slightly longer version of the bitly
link to simplify it but you join me on
camera so I am doing a feel at the
beginning of each of these to tell us
what we are doing what this is so I'm
part of a technology cooperative called
together Tech right now under that
umbrella we're working together to as
project owners to facilitate each
other's projects so what kind of
infrastructure what kind of systems do
we need in place to be able to bring our
ideas into the world and that is just
very much a project of projects my
project is solution raising solution
raising is in our long conversation that
generates actual solutions we could
implement right now if we had 10,000
people and $100,000 I am also looking to
create the process together that helps
us actually work together with 10,000
people or more to create solutions so to
generate an idea as well as get the idea
into the world that's like a combination
of project management decision-making
and governance how does it look to
actually make decisions together so I am
going live every morning at 8:30 to be
able to find people who want to work on
it and discuss ideas and my kids just
woke up Vietnam gun line in just gonna
stand there what do you think I do turn
these mornings just sit here and talk
that's pretty accurate
I like your I like your outfit and your
hairdo it was very quick you get dressed
faster than I do if you want you get
yourself
cereal otherwise I look I can get you
something yeah all right but can you
please eat it somewhere that isn't right
here so I've known appreciated in the
cupboard with goals or there might be
some in the dish rack there I don't know
all right I love my could be Don has
three beers but
so of anyone who pops in can can be part
of do they can rewatch the beginning
stay out of it the idea is they can
watch the beginning of any of the live
videos and then get an idea of what it
is weird we are doing i would love these
hour-long in the morning to become
basically the board meetings much more
fun for the the process would see how we
actually creating a process that we
could do as a contest
media applications whatever it is that
involves 10,000 people to actually
create an idea so that they feel like
they're they're actually owners of that
idea at whatever level they want to
participate so they want to be on the
board of directors have full account i
have them on camera participation or
whether they want to just watch and vote
on things we don't have a system yet to
vote so we're gonna be creating that in
certain loads where is the cereal that's
a good question right here this one
right yeah mark need not my balls
sometimes to find things are you getting
it okay and so tomorrow i have people
committed to coming and being on for a
what I'm hoping will be a regular weekly
Wednesday morning solution raising live
sorry miss portion I'm just gonna wait
for my captain for cereal and you get it
ready go this is the sound you're
starting to but it's gonna be
you
all right I don't know maybe other
people can can deal with the crinkly
another bag but I don't much like it if
I could not listen to it I would not
listen to the milks on the top my love
there you go
usually she's out much earlier than my
8:30 session so I can help her get her
breakfast and do all that and today is
she was that dick she woke up five
minutes before 8:30 hey life in the
quarantine who needs a schedule you'd
have to be at school in 25 minutes if
we'd have to leave in 10 minutes at the
school today when I'm done this we're
gonna set up Microsoft teams for your
class uh-huh I know an hours we're at
the school working a that's the freezer
closed that open the next one next year
no beans please just hurry okay okay hey
Julie how's it going this morning you
can't see this that's fine I'm sorry
yeah I wanted to try you know just
because I'm walking with my past as you
can hear the background so I'm pushing
the stroller exactly so we're walking
moving around and I don't know I mean
you you define the scope or the frame of
this right if you say it's not we cannot
hang out or you need to focus then I
will leave the conversation but even
though we are learning it as we do yeah
absolutely I don't hear you anymore
do you know that I've been doing
something similar you know like a live
streaming on YouTube and Facebook
I'm just switching locations granted I'm
telling her to go eat somewhere that's
not the kitchen table cereal work out so
well I'm trying to go and now I just
moved all of my waters and southern
waters it's interesting this dynamic of
doing things in public it creates this
frame that it needs to be you know high
quality and official there is this sense
of officiality and right now we are kind
of breaking all the frames yes yes
absolutely
which is also half less because like all
the people who are not normally used to
having much more professional chat likes
shows like yeah what actual television
I've had to downgrade theirs because
they don't have the staff they don't
have people they don't just have the
process that's normally there there is a
there's a convergence all right
rest of its kind of get to try it to try
this see how it works it's like Edna's
lives or anything hour whatever is
happening in life is happening oh yeah
no I've seen that you've got live a few
times I keep wanting to pop in but what
time you usually go it's usually do you
don't have any set time right it's just
uh I do actually I mean it's I live in
Switzerland and so basically I have time
in the evening sorry it's a bit windy
let's see if I can cover my head's a bit
[Music]
better okay so I mean right now I'm
working from home with my wife and we're
both working part time but we have to
take care of my son and so
the day is pretty much filled
except maybe right now given that we're
just strolling but then I have time to
do some game B activity in the evenings
for me all right
9 10 11 p.m. that's more or less the
time where I appear and livestream a bit
but you know like I would rather he
doesn't need to be on my channel right
like or your channel I would prefer
there to be kind of like a space where
you see that there are conversations
that are going on and you just join them
and they stop some may be scheduled some
not but you know like I called it the
digital patio you know or a digital
courtyard courtyard Oh patio yeah no I
saw your your posted in game be a game
be whose furnace wkb things right it's
like all the sub sub parts - I think
they the game be cafe was kind of like
that but it didn't quite work out as far
as popping in and having people in there
but we haven't tried it during the
pandemic or so many people are home and
looking for a connection I think it
might be more possible right now I mean
I have an opinion about the digital
about the game be cut off your house
because you know it was my friends who
built that you know Wendy and Christian
and I've been using it with them since
then you know whenever we have a call we
use it
so in principle someone could still hop
in but it never happens anymore but so
my sense about that is that it's just
one conversation right so and I would
rather have a place where there might be
a number of conversations going on at
the same time so it's like at maybe a
higher level than the individual zoom or
you know video chat more like a place
where you can see what what kind of
conversations are going on and if you
want you start one and then people can
get notified right so you
see Nick entered the patio right or Nick
started a conversation you want to join
like and then so it would be kind of
more like a list of ongoing
conversations and maybe you would even
see like a snapshot of who's inside and
this is my kind of my vision problem
with the game people coffee house was
basically notifications right people
don't know when someone is online yeah
absolutely and that's a big like if
there's enough pop you know if there
were a million people using that it
wouldn't be a problem because they're
always being there'd be too many people
there and that would be unusable on the
other side but yes having a digital like
like what you said a digital patio that
helps you form those conversations and
you can pop on when you're free and see
who else is available and what you can
join and what you can can leave um I
think was Jordan Hall who told me about
a specific kind of calm conversation
because I'm of course the idea cafes
after the World Cafe and we were talking
about those type of conversations of
having a large group of people rotate
between tables and there's another one
it's called circle or something it's not
circling which of courses like I sensed
on that something and Jordan I don't
think all it sort of circling my friends
by the friend called circling but like
you go in and leave conversations as you
want so there's a main room and never
got in a conversation you go back there
and whenever anyone else joins you can
decide on a topic and then go and be
part of a table and anyone can join that
generally those don't join it you you go
to the main meeting room and you you
wait until there's other people to have
a conversation but with your feet so if
the conversation isn't if people are
showing up in a way you don't like or
the conversations going way you don't
like you're totally allowed you of
course you're allowed to leave like it's
part of the culture that you just cuz
you don't know why someone left they
might have just been there for enough
time and other people want to be you
know and having something cooler to that
with it's digital yeah I was wondering
whether you are talking about something
physical yeah there's a few ways in a
physical place usually there's a bunch
of sirens and then one common meeting
place when you're done with yours
back and when there's three or four
people you then decide on a topic you
want to discuss and then you go and
discuss it and people can digital
version of that is more or less yeah but
I would like to see actually yes yeah
maybe an additional layer would be
really that even if you're offline that
you might say okay where if Jordan
Jordan Hall appears in the party that I
want to be notified right like I'm fine
being disrupted in whatever I'm doing
you know that kind of thing
it'd be good to have your notifications
more hierarchical where you're like okay
I don't want everything in facebook but
when this person posts this is what I
want they all have one option like
YouTube this is the little bell it's yep
too much of like if you put it on
everything you get too many
notifications so it's like I just really
actually just want to know when the
people I follow go live that's all yes
yeah otherwise I don't I can watch it
whenever but live is a different a
different context I had an idea
yesterday which I have run by nobody and
I posted up and game B it's one of those
things where I don't really want to take
it on but I would like participate in it
which is there's so many people like I
think a lot of us have found that the
conversations are the thing they're the
best part I mean especially with who
you're having conversation with and I
think there's those of us who are okay
finding people to have conversations
with and people who that's more of a
difficult task and even for us that it's
not a difficult task like I'm gonna
reach out to people like I've had a
couple of conversations in Jordan hall
and anyone who has a project and like
ooh I want to find out more about that I
reach out and try to set up a
conversation with them but what I would
like anyway so my idea was to do almost
like a I don't know if you've ever done
like chain letters when you were a kid
where you like you will get stickers in
the mail or something you'll send it to
for people who will send it to for
people to send to for people and the
math never went you know you end up with
like a million stories right forgiving
out five or whatever um doing so the
idea this is a lot of run in versus
somewhat simple idea is so like you and
I started let's say right and we
a conversation and then our job is to
match each other with somebody else that
we think they would enjoy a conversation
with and we give them the topic or they
can decide on a topic together whichever
one works for them so if they have it's
you know rule Omega or Cove in 1900 I
don't know what the topics would be we
can generate a bunch of like twelve
different topics so the people who can't
generate them could just take one right
roll the wheel you're talking about this
today parenting are you parents um yeah
after you've had the conversation you're
each so if it's weekly saying I would
have a comment always set up with the
person before noon right so whoever you
set me up it's got the call I didn't
hear the last ten seconds I'm sorry I
was like Abby was trying to have a
conversation just so we ever two people
started to be you and I could be me and
Eric whoever starts it we then I then
match Eric up with somebody whether he's
had a conversation with them or not
doesn't really matter it's just that we
each set each other up with a comment
with a partner a person if two people
have to figure out what time works for
them in the next week or so you can you
have people in different times know
people who liked wanting to have a
conversation every month could have
conversation a free month was the one in
every week could have it every week for
the point is suggest that like a one
person needs to start two people sorry
needs to start it and then you'll each
go off like every week I would have a
different conversation with somebody new
the first time would be with you and
then you set me up with Eric and then
Eric would set me up with Wendy and
Wendy would say you don't like the idea
in those generates not because we could
have people in a moment because
absolutely this is a game among many
that could be done right in that sense I
like how Peter Limburg is kind of like
providing this general space for a
number of different experiments but
I wonder whether such a formal structure
would go far right because people have
yeah busy lives and each person has
their own favorite way of going about
these things about like a dance card
right or like you'd be like yes you can
met like again those of us who are more
well-known in the gaming be space
because we're so I'm part of so many
videos and part of so many conversations
most of the people's first idea right so
I'm not gonna have more than one idea
one conversation a week so if someone's
already matched up I'm not gonna you
don't even accept a second one so you
have to find somebody else and in so
doing we're gonna we want to generate
within the game beats face people who
wanted this alright it go if you're
brand new and you don't know how to
start a conversation you just put your
name on a list and if I can't find
somebody amongst to like there's one I
won't really want you to talk to you I'm
dying for you to talk to them I think
that you'd have a lot in common I can
just pick a random person right it might
be a really amazing pump fiction be like
alright I'm picking this person maybe
because you guys had conflict because I
thought you'd get along or just it's
just completely random but you have a
list of people who are open to this
process who maybe aren't as as well
known by name and picture right and so
and working through the process always
if like what's working what's not
working what feels fun what feels
arduous how do we mix the arduous piece
and keep the fun piece and it goes on
for four weeks you know eight
conversations we had actually I don't
know two or eight twelve fourteen
fourteen gorgeous this is difficult with
kind of landscape that's broad off that
you can't you can't go in the grass or
is that just for greatness I'm out there
is a just farm next to me so this is
where the cows spend their time so I'm
really out close I mean the suburbs here
are very close to now
okay anyway my place I scheduling is a
pain I don't want to schedule what they
want I will show up and say now I have
time right and whoever is around then
conversation that's more and honestly
this Ari I like this idea that's a good
element zero I got to have having the VR
chat room where we get closer to them
you hear them louder I mean that
wouldn't work for me by hearing but I
something in VR where I like when you're
it's like an actual room we can go up
and say hey enjoy be ours also a lot
harder it's actually alright sorry it's
time for me to leave it's nice to be on
switch Traci during this time period so
we won't have guests pop in hi alright
now now treat ailments Gomez I have
trouble doing both at the same time I
was you can see my kids dry it's been in
a few things I need to get her to me do
one I just get her to redo it I need new
art on my whiteboard which is there for
anything but my kids drives but it ends
up he would stay instead the longest but
when it was him without his camera on so
it was just him black and then I'm in a
black hoodie against the black
background it was way too much black it
was like I was just one floating head so
I decided to turn it right or not be all
ready yet it's becoming increasingly
clear to me that sounds clearly come I
agree it is absolutely like there's it's
weird like my
kid is on facebook messenger she's seven
and most people me included even though
my kids constantly on a tablet
I wouldn't necessarily have been
comfortable with her having kids
messenger but she can just call whoever
she wants like the parent is the is the
arbitrator we get to decide who our kids
are connected to and so we like I rude
request my her friends from her friend's
mom or dad to can she add you but then
once they're added to it they can just
call each other whenever they want so
it's kind of a interesting a neat
because the community were part of that
we don't live in but they all live there
and they're in and out of each other's
houses all the time right now they can't
do that so they have set this up so they
can kind of be in and out of each
other's houses digitally so she's now
connected to all of our neighbors who
are neighbors as well as her old
schoolmates she had a conversation
yesterday for other schoolmates and then
her so it's like people I know whose
kids are much less on the tablets they
have like maybe an hour of screen time
the day are like yes messenger here talk
to other people like we're upping our
lowering our bar of like allowing our
kids to be on it and upping ello Randy
are you element 0 oh yeah all right just
mean the camera is not working or okay
no I just had the YouTube playing also
so I was hearing your voice from the
YouTube and yes we're good in leg two
stereo never too good yeah your knee in
there if I closed now over there oh that
is closed but you might be hearing
feedback okay sometimes that just
happens where I can hear myself I'm just
gonna drop you out and back and you can
also just reek lick on the link let me
just see sometimes women sometimes you
have to go out and then back in and then
I'm gonna switch to headphones that
could pick you feedback that will
absolutely
it's not feedback yes just an echo okay
truth is that it's all working out it's
technology because it's also like so
many people when you can zoom already in
them in this pandemic hit zoom went sky
rocketed
everyone's on soon people hadn't heard
of the zoom or using zoom and so they
don't have enough bandwidth like they
don't they to haven't figured out their
service for that many people and I think
that's part of the disservice of game a
is that to some degree you can't own
that right you can't be like listen you
know like we were working it was we were
working out our kinks but now there's
like millions of people where they used
to be tens of thousands on we're gonna
have some growing pains during this time
period but in order for them to say that
then you lose trust in them and then you
know like instead of them I don't know
like bringing you into the process like
here's where we are return to fix it but
we can only do it so fast it's like yeah
well just let everyone's calls kind of
be a little bit shitty I don't know
currency is not incentivized in many
cases no its disincentivizes but I do
think that when you're a for-profit
business that operates for-profit then
you need that secrecy where is when it's
something we own together and we want it
to succeed therefore we want to know
what's working and what's not working we
want more transparency so that we could
offer solutions right I think there's a
certain sense of what's the word
ownership that's not the right word but
like if I'm if I'm an employee a
customer to a business I want good
customer service and I want them to go
above and beyond I want make no mistakes
if they make mistakes I'm gonna make
right plus some whereas like if I go to
a restaurant and they make my boil you
would expect with an individual what are
you an individual to display sorry
you're breaking up okay
I can't hear you I can try speaking
closer to my mic ethanol's is just laggy
yeah no that's good yep
okay so yeah I was just making the brief
comment that you ideally would expect a
corporation to behave like an indoor you
would have the same expectations of a
corporation I believe you would have an
image of a friend you want them to do
what they say they're gonna do be on it
and be and I guess that's the difference
this is like what a corporate like if I
go to a restaurant and I get food
poisoning I do because it's too much of
a process but but I might feel entitled
to sue right I might leave I could
easily sue
whereas I went to a friend's house and
they gave me food poisoning I might not
eat there again but I definitely
wouldn't sue them right like I wouldn't
sure there's a different level of both
that like we've required to not know how
the sausage is met and we put on them
that they are supposed to fix it like we
want we don't take ownership of the
problem right I can't offer Amazon a
solution I can just say you didn't get
me my shipment in two days like you were
supposed to I can't actually help
improve that system whereas when we own
something together it's a much more
dynamic because it's like okay people
aren't getting there like right now
during the pandemic two days shipping is
out the window people that like the
supply chains disrupted there's way more
way more people Amazon guarantee you is
gonna break their employees over this
whereas if we own Amazon we could be
like yes we want employees to be well
treated and we understand that during
this time period it's anyone who's
working is under more stress because you
have to go to a physical place where
there's people and hopefully or to
someone who's not more highly
susceptible to cope at 19 but I don't
know like if there was transparency we
could figure it out together we could
work through it but right now it's this
like division of like customer and
corporation where we expect them to
almost be perfect and because of that
they have to keep secrets and then we
get mad about the secrets when like if
it was transparent than we could have we
could see why right like oh just like we
can see with all of our unemployment
benefits that's on the news constantly
the huge spike in traffic basically
people applying for unemployment we
could see right Amazon's were
people were 100 million and now it's
five billion like it's like oh okay I
see we see why so and we could create a
system that helped instead of them
having to hierarchy down I'm like okay
medical supplies clearly have to get
shipped once but the thing is if
everyone's never in supplies Aaron right
then in any one if we all are seeing the
same picture the same net a picture of
the whole company and everyone in it
and we all know that we're all seeing it
then we can trust each other and anyone
who does have the solution can step up
broadcast it to everybody
mm-hmm rather than having to go through
all these channels where they could get
the signal could get missed but all
sorts of reasons yeah exactly and there
could be ways to prioritize shipping it
doesn't matter how long of a prime
membership you you know how long you've
been a prime member or whatever our
version is if that is a burden something
we do at all but what matters is that
what is your need for this thing right
now right and that's something that
Amazon should have been still a long
time ago for the good of their employees
I don't always need two days shipping on
something sometimes it could take three
weeks and I'm fine with it other things
I have a higher priority so if we could
input that into the system and it could
figure it out and you could also like
right now during the pandemic they've
made like I ordered hand sanitizer and
face masks six weeks ago and they were
ordered and they were like and then a
week later they were like actually
because of the pandemic we don't have
enough we're gonna say they sent me the
wrong road I thought it wasn't Amazon it
was one of their suppliers but similar
experience with pantry foods and and so
it's like okay I don't know what I'm
getting when I order which is a problem
I don't know how long it's gonna take
but transparency could help with that
then I have someone like my dad who is
on Amazon Prime and although he was
ordering quite regularly before now it's
kind of life or death that he can get it
because if he has to go out to pick
something up he's much more susceptible
so those people should be at a higher
level and they should be able to say
when they can get their thing later
right like yeah I don't need this for
two weeks it's headphones or no I need
this right now because it's my
profession right and if I don't have
headphones tomorrow I'm gonna get fired
or whatever it is
you can put and you can see whether
someone's always a last-minute person
who always needs it shipped overnight
and those people should have more of a
pause to their crime and other any way
that we can figure out the math and
what's working better together when it
started wouldn't work transparent and we
have ownership in it so we're not
leaving you know like I should be able
to fix that same as you I don't
shouldn't leave it to Jeff Bezos right
because then he breaks his employees to
make his customers happy or some places
break their customers to make their
employees happy which is clearly not
going to keep you in business very long
I was actually just watching a
documentary on Jeff Bezos it wasn't it
wasn't that great somebody posted it was
thinking be don't even remember it's
like the rise of the rise and reign of
Jeff Bezos it just wasn't it wasn't bad
either it just wasn't it's the same old
same old about Amazon it's not like
there's anything in there that's new
that's oh that's how they operate it's
like a highly efficient but everyone
looks at him like a visionary and
although yeah I guess so he was also
just in the right place at the right
time like he's not the only one to have
an e-commerce on online yet his is the
one that took off during that time
period and then once you get that
success then you start building the ego
of like yes I'm the one guy and it's
like no actually you were just lucky
enough yeah I heard something once about
how you know when it when they're ruined
initially all of these you know maybe 20
years ago I don't know all these startup
companies in Silicon Valley and they
were looking at all the successful ones
that's why they were successful and you
know figure out okay well these are the
things we do need to do but then it
turned out that like you know the nine
out of ten companies didn't make it they
were also doing all the same thing with
just luck that that taint one made it
not because of the things they were
doing necessarily yeah there's a I don't
know the fallacy very well but there's
like survivor fallacy I know they show
the picture for world war two planes for
they were likes when planes would come
back and have bullet holes in them they
could see where the bullet holes were
and they reinforced those parts but the
problem was it was only the planes that
made it back so when you run shot in a
very critical part like the fuel right
then you explode and you die and so you
don't make it back to normal it
and there's like this survivor one on
the other way self-help people do this
to like and a lot of public speakers
where it's like well I could do this I
did look at me and my successful TED
talk anyone can do this and you're like
no actually only one in a thousand can
make it to where you are even trying and
so but the more successful somebody is
the more platform they have to say how
they got to their success but we don't
ever take the actual metrics okay but
how many people did all of that and
didn't get to success it's somehow your
fault that you didn't write you did you
woke up meditated Ran's and everything
that Tony Robbins does but you never
make it to Tony Robbins success in fact
we never have more than one client
that's not is it on you like you
followed the rules and so I mean I'm
figuring out that the rules are
completely broken and it's more about
your own internal guide that you can't
really base on anyone else cuz otherwise
you're following the rules and you're
miserable because you're not getting
this success if you follow the rules and
get the success which let's say 1% of
people do
then you're the commercial for the next
generation then you're like right look
at me I got success because I followed
these rules right but you're only
showcasing one in a hundred people what
about the other 99 you didn't get there
even though they followed the same thing
if that makes make sense yeah yeah
basically I mean this is your show um I
just was inspired to pop in and and say
hi it's a lot easier than typing I saw
your show yesterday and I was just
really genuinely moved and inspired by
your vulnerability it's not something
that everybody is cut out to do but I
think these times you know we all need
to step up and be more vulnerable to
each other if we want to form genuine
connections um so yeah seeing you speak
yesterday really it inspired me I guess
I've always been sort of shy and camera
resistant you know and I spent a lot of
time typing but not necessarily a lot of
times speaking so my confidence in my
speaking is it the greatest no but it is
something I've been working on for some
time though
I mean part like my main reason for
joining was just like introduce myself
and also I find out I woke up this
morning and I found that I was genuinely
excited to see oh yeah Jubilee should be
on I hope he gets a heart I'm really
glad to see you're doing it because I
know you know you expressed what it
means to you yesterday how you you just
want to have the structure or again I'm
just doing my best to speak here yeah no
that's that's it's it's if I'm giving
nothing to the world except giving
people permission to show up as they are
I think I'm doing a pretty fantastic job
and that is although it's not
necessarily my purpose it's continually
the feedback I get from other people
like oh you are you're going live and
you're don't look professional so like I
can do this too and I'm like yes exactly
so anyone you were saying that um you
don't think you're you're working on
your speech and you don't think it's
it's where you want it to be it's my
paraphrasing and what you just said and
I was just before I went live thinking
about public speaking because I don't
I'm not great at it
in fact I'm much better at a
conversation that I am broadcasting so
they to the camera but it's the best
iconic can do at the moment
but it's it's like we have a choice do
you play in it until you can get better
at it and just allow it to be what it is
or how good do you have to be at it
before you attempt it right in public in
private and whatever whatever realm that
you're comfortable in it right like it's
takes something to step up and join this
even on voice right that you put
yourself out there and it's vulnerable
to do that and I guess I would just
invite everyone to play in the muck as
much as possible like you can't actually
learn to be part of a conversation and
speak better until you're part of it and
I can tell you I've been doing this for
years that I'm not learning to speak
better because my brain can't pick the
word out so and it's gonna lose train of
thought and I have a lot of filler
language I know from doing some of those
masters sorry oh I was just gonna throw
in
one one factor to me having is that I
was I was actually I have a DD so I was
on adderall for like ten years of my
life and I was a coder and I was able I
was you know a pretty kick-ass oder in
my opinion but like the adderall has
side effects the physical side effects
so for about a year now about a year ago
I went off of it and it's like I found
that I just couldn't code anymore or at
least I needed a break from and now I'm
trying to figure out okay can I go back
and do this without being on that or oh
yeah it's not it's not easy
iseman been my motivation mm-hmm and my
confidence in speaking with people and
feeling like oh okay
oh my god I haven't been employed
because I've given myself that freedom
to have that time off to recover and I
was like well jeez can I can i code what
there's been there's this pandemic and
it's okay like I was just gonna join
that a service called TaskRabbit where
you just go and help people out with
groceries simple but then the pandemic
hit and it's like well okay a lot of
those tax or not advisable because of
contagion so you know I tried to figure
out how can I contribute and I've just
realized like really being honest with
myself and like watching your video
yesterday okay I just need to take that
baby step like starting to talk to
people
bake me some bread and like
maybe if there's something really
inspired by that I would be like I would
be a little bit this really just all the
complexity that got to be too much in
the past but if it could be something
it's relatively simple
not like a huge team of people and maybe
I could start can you not code now
because how do I ask this because
there's like an outside bar you can't
meet like the clients the boss you can't
let's say before it took you two weeks
to code something to know it's going to
take you six weeks or a month or is it
that you can't even do a six-week prose
like you can't even do it with triple or
quadruple the time period it's yeah
there's some of that and there's some of
just like psychological emotional like
resistance like I'm a computer I start
to code and it's just like physically
you know I don't want to do that is
rewarding
ya know which is an important thing to
know I'm also a IDI
I'm also autistic I think and I got I
didn't get died I haven't gotten
diagnosed with autism but well I went in
to get a DD meds which I don't take
daily for other reasons but I wanted to
have for like once a week or once every
couple weeks when I want to take them
because I know that I'm a DD and I know
what I actually took one of my old
roommates was that I was like oh this is
what this feels like to be somewhat
neurotypical and I can't do it daily
because it hurts my sleep it has the
side effects so I can do it
you know once once a week and pay that
price but I it is so common the people
with a DB learn to cram information into
their brain with adrenaline and we all
eventually have a burr knows whether
you're on medication or not you're on
medication eventually it stops like
eventually you have to get off of it and
then you have to figure out how your
brain actually works without it when it
was kind of addicted to substance to
work in a way the world wanted it to
work and you wanted it to work or like
me you don't take it you figure out how
your brain works and I can take it as a
one-off but either way once I
started truly embracing my
neurodiversity where I allow my brain to
lose its train of thought I allow it to
badd in autistic and whatever it shows
up in the moment it doesn't look the
best when public speaking but in doing
so I've tapped into a different part of
my genius and a different part of my
purpose that got me to the point where
although I can't explain it because the
public speaking thing I think I know how
we can save the world and create me
together and it's not a one it didn't
come to me in a download ten years ago
and now it's like it's continual it's
like oh that's how we do that thing and
that thing and that thing and if I the
more I try to force it and try to be
what society or neurotypical I'm
supposed to be it all breaks apart but
when I just allow it I can feel like the
genius in magic and it's not all day
every day but it's like the sparks of
things that come up and so I guess my
suggestion if you want to take it is
that like there is something in your
brain that doesn't necessarily need the
medication if you're not able to take it
and when you let go of what that's
supposed to look like you get what it
actually is and you might fit into
society less but like the payoff as to
what you then can give from that space
is huge and I don't because I'm the only
one I know who's like been through that
journey and my exact brain journey and
so much brain changes throughout my life
I don't know if it works for other
people but but there's so much magic and
possibility here that I'm like it can't
not like there's something about when
you live your own life and you allow
things to just happen that you start to
realize there's something orchestrating
something because it's way too weird for
it not to be for it to be what's the
word like a coincidence on repeat like
okay this is design that says I guess my
analogy is like if a TD people are put
and autistic people and brain damage and
any kind of neurodiversity are put here
to be exactly what they're supposed to
be we're supposed to have 15 thoughts at
once and not be able to necessarily
communicate them we're supposed to let
the train and the trail kind of do
derail and yet you all seem to build up
a conversation with
able to actually have ideas that if
they're who they're supposed to be and
if we allowed them to be who they were
supposed to be we get their best self
but all of society is about performance
this is what you're supposed to be be it
or you can't be it right you can't vote
for six weeks you have to code in two
weeks or you can't do this you have to
live off caffeine or you can't code you
have to instead of like what how can we
support you - it's a lot of code you're
about sustainable and it's not it's not
sustainable for anyone but the burnout
rate is higher of course for autistic
and and and EDD people and there's more
of us coming through so like the 20 year
olds he come and still be on adderall
and still you know play that game but
once we hit late 30s 40s we can't play
the I don't know I'm having been on
medication fighting for my whole life I
haven't been on medication all for an
extended period of time for a TD but
because I and I know how my brain works
and I went through University and I went
through high school and then when my
brain changed from my brain tumors and I
couldn't use the journal and in a
different way that happens with AD
people I just clicked like my nervous
system shuts down so I was like well I
don't the tools I had to make my brain
work no longer work what do I do and it
turns out what I did was just surrender
to it like all right what do I got what
do I got from this space because trying
to make it work for society or trying to
be a version of myself that would fit
into society broke me in a way that I
don't know society never could like it
was just I was breaking myself to fit in
and once I stopped doing that it was
like oh now I don't really care like I
don't care on and it was it's been a
process like every cycle of the process
is like I care a little less what other
people think of me and I know a little
more who I actually am and every time it
proves itself more and more of like oh I
get this piece when I do this and this
piece when I do this so anyway that was
me running on for a while but yeah one
thing that I have found does help me
with virtually no side effects though is
the it's qualia have you heard of qualia
the neurotropic sac
now that out there by a neuro hacker
collective which Daniel Schwarzenberg er
is like he's one of the office not the
CEO but he's like I think his brother is
this via that's how I found Daniel's
watching Berger actually um but it
definitely helps me work with clarity
and focus I highly recommend it
you know for anyone who can afford it
it's like 60 bucks a month yeah that's I
this is just me following my own
guidance in no way if it's helping you
that's awesome but like I got the
guidance a long time ago then unless it
was free or cheap I'm not it's not
something I'm doing for my brain so like
if Daniel or Jordan wanted to be like
here try neuro hacker try this I would
try it but and give my honest feedback
as to whether or not three months in it
helped in any way but I find placebo and
nocebo effect are way too strong in in
my life and so I was spending a lot of
money my family's obsessed with
supplements and even now I'll take I
haven't taken the greatest medication
off anyway
it'll be like double it triple it
quadruple it I'm like no that's not the
diminishing rate of returns we need
nutrients but like how many do you need
and how expensive it is it and why is it
so expensive and what is it to eat and
can power in a game a model of course
supplements are $60 a month in game B
it's like the very people who need it
the most people who are brain-damaged
people who have had a brain events that
that changes their brain and people who
are born neurodiverse could be the
people who could use it the most and yet
at the same time they're often the
people who can't afford it right you're
less likely to be as employed at a
higher level if you're a BD and not on
medication if you're autistic if you're
definitely brain damaged which I don't
put any other two I don't think the
other two every damage but I have all
300 on trios um that like if that's
truly what we need to make our brains
work then it needs to be accessible to
everyone which means we need to swap
supply and demand instead of like are
you willing to pay $60 for it how much
does it cost us to make it how many
people want it and at what price point
how many people do we need to bring it
down to that price point because I
guarantee you
basically no drug unless they're like
they cost 60 bucks a month to produce it
should be I don't know 20 bucks or less
and I don't know I don't think even
transparent so then you can no sorry I
said I don't know you'd have to talk to
them about why they priced it at that
but I know it used to be like 150 and
they brought it down but I mean it yeah
in my mind I think it's a great thing
that's doing but yeah obviously in an
ideal gaming world sure you know that
everybody gets it for free but I think
it's a you know is the first step you
you often need to start a game a world
figure out how to make a sustainable
economy I mean I'm going a different a
different route but because that is the
part of my issue is right so you have to
play a game in order to get enough money
in order to put food on the table in
order to be able to say like have space
to be able to play game b-but I don't
think the people who are successful in
game a actually know how to create game
B and I mean all of them I mean Daniel I
mean Jordan I mean like as brilliant as
they are in starting it and catalyzing
it they actually don't know how to get
there because that hurts their business
right if this is how I put food on the
table and this is how I do that
I can't envision a world where this
doesn't exist even if it would be more
powerful even if that would help more
people even if it's like you just have
these blocks to to those solutions it's
the people who it doesn't work for who
in my experience can can create a new a
new system but then they don't know how
to implement it because they're not game
a people and so it's about finding that
process finding the finding how we get
the best ideas out there how if you're
in business if you're in life for a
purpose let's say you create a brain
drug and are you in it to make money or
you in it to help people's neuro health
because you can only serve one of those
masters so it doesn't mean you can't be
profitable right I'm not talking about
giving it away for free I'm talking
about having transparency on the cost
and showcasing that it's as close to
that as possible that it takes to run
the company and to pay us play our staff
a living wage
everyone in this in the supply chain
yeah that's a very different process
than like oh and we priced her to 150
and not enough people were buying it so
we moved it to 60 it's you can make that
decision yeah sorry I'm not sure that
that's the case yeah no no you can undo
this by I you can also if your purpose
is to help more people maybe they moved
it down to 60 because they realize they
could use like let's say under 150 model
you're making a million dollars profit a
year and under the sixty dollar model
you're selling to way more people and
you're also making a million dollars
profit here of course it makes sense if
you're in any way attached to your
purpose to have more customers and move
over to this short but less expensive
but if moving to $60 meant you gotta
impact a hundred fold times but you
brought your your profit from a million
down to let's say 750 thousand would you
make that decision
you're still profitable even away and
that's the question and I don't think
most game a business people
understandably would make the decision
to make less profit even if it had more
purpose and that is if it's equal I
think everyone's gonna choose to have
more purpose but when it costs you your
profit which is your master which one is
the one you're gonna choose and I'm not
saying they did one or the other just
that when you're playing that game if
you're not even aware of it and you're
it's like well no think about all the
good I could do for $250,000 right but
is the good you're doing the reason
you're in business if the reason you're
in business is to help people's
neurological function and you can impact
more people what could you do with that
250,000 that isn't that right then you
should be in business doing that like
it's like I'm very focused on on
creating solutions for purpose instead
of profit but you can't do neither right
less right you need to have although you
only have one master you serve you have
to acknowledge both of them you can't be
in business for purpose without any
money in resources and you can't be in
business purely for profit or you're
gonna piss everyone off and no one's
gonna give you money right it's so like
there's a balancing act
but it's which one is your master which
one is your bottom line what you're
going to decide to do things for and 99%
of game a is for profit yeah but again
if they gave it to me for free of it
absolutely like to see what this does
for you because that's also I mean
supplements is is something that has the
potential to help in a really big way
then like pharmaceuticals and stuff
don't because they're about keeping you
healthy and getting you back to to
baseline or better than baseline versus
needing to correct something that maybe
didn't need to be corrected it has all
these side effects one one point that
was welcomed a TD one sake
definitely know hardly anything about
hurricanes but I did watch the talk gave
in which the general concept was like
everything that they put in in the
Sequoia is like designed to help the
brain do what it already does better
like the whole different philosophy then
say a certain antidepressants or other
drugs which like target forget a
specific receptor philosophy being that
the brain is a complex system so you can
expect like one variable and fix the
problem it's going to affect all the
signal of what it's already doing I know
that's kind of a vague description but
that's that's my understanding
ya know and that's again I don't I mean
I do know a little bit about neurology
because of my health system and cuz my
background is in biology but I wouldn't
know enough to know whether or not that
is true or not right like whether or not
and I don't I don't think that Daniel
and Jordan watching them speak is
speaking to Jordan I've never spoken to
Daniel I don't think they're nefarious
in any way shape or form I just think
it's natural when you have your food and
shelter provided by something for you
not to be able to see everything and
what yeah I I would say I think that
would be a very good conversation the
for somebody to have there's some point
of time or maybe they have it yeah like
it business some degree is in direct
opposition to be right well or at least
the way it currently is yeah and I guess
that's like especially for brains in
general there's this idea that what a
peak brain looks like right and so we
want to get as close to that as possible
and I think that very assumption is
broken and this is why if game a works
for you you can envision game B as
somebody who I've had autism my whole
life without knowing it cuz I Lin knew
it last year I've had a DD my whole life
with knowing it and I've had brain
damage since that is like an ongoing it
still is is getting worse and worse from
my brain swelling after brain surgery
and I go and or going radiation and a
gene and B tamam and all this stuff but
there is something I've tapped into by
going with what my brain is that I would
never have if I needed it to act a
certain way and so although taking a
supplement again totally valid if it's
helping you reach peak the fact we want
everyone to reach peak is ridiculous
because you're not giving who you are
you're giving what we think you're
supposed to give which is kind of like
taking the ATD medication to improve
your brain without the side effects I
think having it available it cost so
there's an it's an option for everyone
and that cost there can be waste off put
it even if you can't afford 20 bucks a
month but if it's available to everyone
because it does truly help otherwise
what you're doing is you're creating
something like anyone who could afford
60 bucks a month for it for a drug that
is optional right it's not your diabetes
medication is going to keep you alive
probably has a somewhat affluent history
and existing life right they probably
weren't born in a flow Bella they
probably weren't like those are the
people who need it even more cuz they
didn't have adequate nutrition when they
were a kid but are the very people who
can't afford it and so it's like either
this is important and we want everyone's
brain working at peak which means
everyone needs this or it's just a new
piece of privilege that the privileged
to get right that's like well if you
could afford this you
get even better you can get an end right
which could potentially make the gap
between rich and poor even greater right
instead of like just embracing your
brain is what it is
who you are is exactly what you have to
give the world there's this thing that
can improve your brain do you want it to
be improved and then it's not Gattaca
it's not survival of the richest fittest
smartest it's like who are you and how
can we help you reach what you feel is
your peak in mental and physical in
whatever you want to focus on because
there's also just that focus right some
people don't care about their mental and
they're not supposed to and other people
like I don't necessarily care about my
physical so much kind of paying the
price for that but that's that's okay
but it's a that we if there's something
in me that screams so loudly that we
need the diversity that exists on this
planet we're not all supposed to be
improving ourselves to some outside
ideal we're supposed to be looking
inside to if to accept and love
ourselves as we are
and then that's naturally how it leads
to progression and then whatever comes
out of that is what's supposed to come
out of it as opposed to who do I want to
be who do and then trying to be that and
tried you know what I mean I want to be
someone who doesn't lose my train of
thought I want to be someone who sounds
like her neurotypical so I can get my
idea across if I could just check that
box and sign up for that of course I
would but I would lose everything that
comes from my neurodiversity I didn't
consciously sign up for in this life
yeah yeah I think I hear you like one
counterexample story to be over for
example from personal experience is like
depression like I'm not going to be like
well I guess I was born with depression
so I shouldn't take antidepressants
because this is like I'm going to
contribute my depression over you know
it's like I'm completely useless and
suffering absolutely and I have another
call at 10 in half an hour so I'm gonna
have to get off this right away but I
guess what it's not
I don't discount anyone who's on any
drug if you're taking antidepressants if
you're taking SSRIs if you're taking if
it's getting
you through your life and you're doing
it that is part of who you need to be
like that it's not drugs are bad only do
what's natural it's like coming from the
inside why do you do this right so for
some people that's taking drugs I took
anti-anxiety meds for three months last
year and it was exactly what I needed to
do because they were the wrong empty
anxiety meds and I went off a pot during
the same time and then when I finally
was like hey cool I'm gonna go off them
I ensign he actually went down because
they were the wrong meds but that's a
whole other story but it's not like as I
was desperate I'm like I'm snapping at
my kid this anxiety is getting too much
for me I need this but it came from
inside because my doctors have been like
you need to go on this you need to go on
that like I don't if I need to take a
drug to function in society to me it's
society that's broken not me and yet I
haven't dropped like it's if you need
antidepressants take antidepressants
if sixty percent of our population needs
antidepressants its society that needs
to figure out its depression problem not
the individual and unfortunately we can
only deal with at an individual level so
of course you need to take the drugs
whereas if instead we can be like why
are you depressed we didn't have
depression problems generally speaking
we were in tribal societies when we were
connected to people when like I get that
the drug model is that your brain is
lacking a chemical I think for some
people that's true and for a lot of
people it's like do you have a purpose
do you know who you are and are you
connected to other people and in order
to get anywhere on that journey you need
to take drugs of any kind yes especially
if it's coming from inside of you
especially if it's like this is the
thing I'm supposed to do with the
consult the consultation of your doctor
it's there's not one prescription that's
a pun because I don't mean frog
prescription but like there's not one
thing that works for everyone
it's about does it resonate with you
does this work right now and then owning
it right like yes I'm on these because I
don't want to be depressed and society
it's a little bit depressing right and I
think we're about to see a society that
doesn't have access to the
pharmaceuticals they used to and that's
a
people who are on antidepressants and on
anti-anxiety meds and on adderall and on
all of these things if we can't get it
in six months to a year right that's a
different society and we have to switch
society over like we have to fix society
but again all you can do is the personal
level right like you can't fix all of
society I'm trying and it's breaking
like it's no big like I can't take that
drug but I'm just gonna dismantle
capitalism to replace it with something
else
I couldn't possibly small hotels but I
don't want to take but that I can do I
think there's a meme there's a meme
there all right I'm gonna go I'm having
a conversation with the idea cafe in in
half an hour over on the idea cafe
Channel we're talking about what if we
knew the pandemic was coming what we
would have liked to have in place for it
if we had forethought and then tomorrow
during this time slot also Shiloh is is
joining and Kyra and we're gonna talk
about we're gonna have an actual
solution raising here online it's going
to be on mental health and emotional
support so what it does look like I'm
sure pharmaceuticals will come up and
then both in the good and bad and then
what what we we would like it to look
like in the future and then 30 minutes
talking about what could we actually
create if we had 10,000 people and
$100,000 and then I will be back on
Thursday shooting the figuring out
hoping people pop in and have a have a
conversation
this was great Randy thanks for joining
and I hope you come on again it's lovely
chatting with you all right thanks keep
doing your thing
bye ready